I have this wave movement that occurs, which I've drawn here, you see, normally
この波の動きがあるでしょう、ここに描いたように、通常は
it's covered here, you see, it's a somewhat transparent view
ここは覆われているでしょう、これは少し透明な視点です
that we see, that we have the point, the point here, this is what remains of this point, okay,
点が見えるでしょう、ここにある点、これがこの点として残るのです、OK？
this above, you imagine I have this kind of wave, at the moment I have
その上、この種の波があると思ってください、それが起こる瞬間に
this, it creates a kind of suction field.
それは吸引場のようなものを作り出します。
And this suction field, it happens here.
そして、この吸引場はここで形成されます。
And my primitive streak, it's there.
そして、私の原始線はそこにあります。
And then it regresses, little by little, by the descent of Hensen's node, until
そして、それはヘンゼン結節の下降によって、少しずつ退縮し、
it disappears.
消滅します。
But in this movement, it's a superior view that is represented here,
しかし、この動きの中で、ここに示されているのは上からの視点です。
where it's a cut that I see here, and now we're looking at it like this, from a superior view.
ここで見ているのは断面図で、今は上から見ています。
That is to say, above, I have the amniotic cavity.
つまり、その上にはより良い空洞があります。
Here, we see the wave here, if
ここで波が見えるでしょう、もし
you will, which is here, like this.
あなたが望むなら、ここにあるように。
This is what draws here, if I put my finger, poof, I have the notochord.
ここに描かれているのは、もし私が指を置くと、ポンと、脊索が現れるということです。
At the moment this begins, there is a traction behind
これが始まる瞬間に、後ろから牽引が起こります。
that occurs, at the level of the pedicle.
それは茎のレベルで起こります。
And it creates here, this primitive streak that has...
そして、それはここに、この原始線を作り出します。
This primitive streak, in continuity, because it happens at
この原始線は、連続性の中で、なぜならそれは同時に起こるからです。
the same time,
同時に、
we don't have the notochord, then we don't have the line,
脊索ができてから線ができるわけではありません。
all of this appears simultaneously, if you will, approximately in
これらすべては同時に現れます、もしあなたが望むなら、ほぼ
a chronology, but very subtle.
非常に細かい時系列で。
And here, this drawing, it's a cut that I'm making here, and
そして、この図は、ここで私が描いた断面図です。
you see here, there.
ここに見えるでしょう、そこに。
Okay?
OK？
Do you see this movement?
この動きが見えますか？
This is simply the movement of the epithelial cells of
これは単に、上皮細胞の動きです。
the epiblast,
上胚葉の、
so the layer above,
つまり上の層の、
which are pulled towards the center
中心に向かって引っ張られ、
and which come to fill the space that is forming.
そして形成される空間を満たしに来ます。
Because at the moment I have this wave,
なぜなら、この波がある瞬間に、
I have a space that opens between my epiblast and my hypoblast.
私の上胚葉と下胚葉の間に空間が開くからです。
You see?
見えるでしょう？
And it comes to this space, it's here.
そして、それはこの空間に来ます、それはここにあります。
And that's how the intermediate tissue, which we call the
そして、このようにして、中胚葉と呼ばれる中間組織、将来の
mesoblast, future mesoderm, will appear.
中胚葉が現れるのです。